A Guide to the John S. and James L. Knight Foundation records, Audiovisual Materials, RG 7 FA1801
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Removable Media, 1950-2013; 2; 0.38 Cubic Feet 1 letter document box
  - DVD, 1957-2013; 3; 0.1 Cubic Feet
    - The Knight Commission on Intercollegiate Athletics: A Summit on the Collegiate Athlete Experience - Disk 2, 2006 January 30 (Box 1)
    - The Knight Commission on Intercollegiate Athletics: A Summit on the Collegiate Athlete Experience - Disk 3, 2006 January 30 (Box 1)
    - Rebuilding Southern Mississippi, 2005 November 14 (Box 1)
      DVD discs re: Mississippi Rebuilding Forum hosted by the Governor's commission on recovery, rebuilding and renewal. The forum's charge was to come up with ideas and suggestions for the communities to use in their rebuilding and renewal in order to create a Mississippi even better than what Hurricane Katrina had destroyed. Plannners and architects from across America and Europe teamed with local professionals, civic leaders and citizens to create this set of tools to enable Mississippi to rise again as an example of the best and most beautiful communities America has to offer.
      Knight File Number - 4517
    - Knight Foundation Biloxi DVD (Box 1)
    - Mississippi Renewal Forum - Final Presentations - Disk 1 (Box 1)
      Overview, Biloxi, Gulfport, Long Beach, D'lberville.
    - Mississippi Renewal Forum - Final Presentations - Disk 2 (Box 1)
      Overview, Moss Point, Pascagoula, Ocean Springs, Gautier.
    - Mississippi Renewal Forum - Final Presentations - Disk 3 (Box 1)
      Overview, Waveland, Bay St. Louis, Pass Christian.
    - Mississippi Renewal Forum - Final Team Presentations - Disk 4 (Box 1)
      James Barksdale - Govenor's Commission, Anthony Topazi - Infrastructure, Andres Duany - Lead Planner, Transportation Report, Environmental Report, Coding/Architecture Report.
    - Mississippi Renewal Forum - Builders/Developers Presentation - Disk 5 (Box 1)
      James Barksdale - Gov. Commission, Andres Duany - Lead Planner, FEMA - Building Failures.
    - Perkins Activities Central: Cool Programs for Kids and Families - A Community Partners Program funded by the Knight Foundation, 2007 January (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 4600
    - Perkins Activities Central - Stan Hywett Presentation, Slideshow, 2007 January (Box 1)
    - Perkins Activities Central - WKYC VFC Special, Knight Foundation 30 second spot, 2007 January (Box 1)
    - Records Wars, 2007 May (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 4906
      One DVD of a spoof of "Star Wars" highlighting good records practices. Made by KF staff and "starring" George Martinez, Elika Lopez, and Olga Rodriquez. It has been the highlight of every records day since then.
    - Knight Foundation 2006 Annual Report, 2007 May 14 (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 4601
      One DVD containing the complete production files for the 2006 KF Annual Report.
    - Knight Foundation Website, 2007 June 14 (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 4602
      One DVD for Macintosh containing backup of complete KF public website from Records Day 2007.
    - Knight News Challenge NPR Public Service Announcement, 2007 (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 4412
      Announcement is in nine languages. Prepared by Public Interest, a public relations firm.
    - James and John Knight Compilation copied 2008, 1957-1982 (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 4539
      DVD and CD copy of images from the Wolfson Florida Moving Image Archive features snippets of film from WTVJ footage (some without sound). Features images of John and James Knight, Lee Hills and Alvah Chapman, among others. Last part is of John Knight's memorial service and features interviews with Herald staffers and Knight's office.
    - Miami Herald copied 2008, c. 1963 (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 4540
      DVD from the Wolfson Florida Moving Image Archive is a copy of a promotional film made of the Miami Herald about 1963, featuring the new building and equipment.
    - Knight Foundation Board Meeting at the Newseum in Washington, DC on "Media Innovations" - Photos, 2008 September 14-15 (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 4603
    - Knight Foundation Board Meeting at the Newseum in Washington, DC on "Media Innovations" - Disc 1 of 2, 2008 September 14-15 (Box 1)
    - Knight Foundation Board Meeting at the Newseum in Washington, DC on "Media Innovations" - Disc 2 of 2, 2008 September 14-15 (Box 1)
    - Knight Foundation Board Meeting at the Newseum in Washington, DC on "Media Innovations" - Berners-Lee Speech, Quicktime, 2008 September 14 (Box 1)
    - New Media Makers Toolkit, 2006 June (Box 1, Folder 14)
      Knight File Number - 4764
    - Knight Commission on Intercollegiate Athletics: 20 Years of Leadership, 2009 October 25 (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 4604
      Video history of the Commission features interviews and archival materials, some from the Knight Foundation Archives.
    - Knight Commission on Intercollegiate Athletics: 20 Years of Leadership - Program, 2009 October 25 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      Program from the anniversary dinner at which the film was premiered.
    - Final Edition: Journalism According to Jack & Jim Knight, 2009 (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 4727
      Video documentary which tells the story of the Knight family, the Akron Beacon Journal and the rise and fall of Knight-Ridder. Produced and written by Paul Jacoway and Kathleen Endres and directed by Paul Jacoway. Knight Foundation archives material was used for the documentary. Excerpts from an oral history with Jack Knight are heard (the archives contains a transcript of the interview). Also included are interviews with Alberto Ibarguen, Gerald Austen, Marjorie Crane, Gene Roberts and Larry Jinks. Footage includes many pictures of the Knight brothers and other Knight Foundation officers, included Lee Hills, Jim Batten, and Alvah Chapman. One hour in length. NOTE: Jacoway has granted KF permission to post it on its website.
    - Fox Business News Interview with KCIA Co-Chair Brit Kirwan, 2009 November 6 (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 4647
      Segment of Fox Business News interview with Brit Kirwan in which he stressed the need for reforming the college athletic system and in curbing the spiraling costs of college sports. 6:23 minutes.
    - Knight Foundation/FCC Meeting at the Newseum, Washington, DC - Disk 1 of 2, 2010 March 9 (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 4762
      Two discs containing 392 high resolution photographs (color) of the meeting. Includes many of Alberto Ibarguen.
    - Knight Foundation/FCC Meeting at the Newseum, Washington, DC - Disk 2 of 2, 2010 March 9 (Box 1)
    - Random Act of Culture, 2010 May 14 (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 4908
      DVD is of one of the KF-sponsored Random Act of Culture. A string quartet plays at the Miami-Dade County Government Center.
    - Knight Community Information Challenge: Media Learning Seminar, 2010 (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 4909
      DVD briefly highlights KF's annual Media Learning Seminar. Features interviews with several participants on what they have learned at the MLS as well as Trabian Shorters, Alberto Ibarguen and Bob Shieffer.
    - Ernst & Young Tax Records, 2004, 2005, 2006 (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 4911
      Federal & State Tax Returns for 2009 and 2) Amended Form 990T for years 2004-2006, submitted in 2010.
    - The Milledgeville - Baldwin County Virtual Porch, c. 2010 (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 4913
      Proposal prepared by The Georgia Digital Innovation Group to create a "virtual porch" in Milledgeville, GA to increase the community's engagement with its citizens. Beverly Blake is featured, as well as KF's initiative to promote civic engagement.
    - Knight Soul of the Community - Multimedia, 2010-2011 (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 5258
    - Knight Soul of the Community - Report Print Proofs, 2011 January 6 (Box 1)
    - TED Conference, TEDWomen Conference, 2011-2013 (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 4910
      DVD of a Knight Foundation sponsored luncheon at the TED [Technology, Entertainment, Design] Conference. The luncheon features an introduction by Paula Ellis. Also included are two copies of a DVD from TEDWomen "ideas performance" in San Francisco in 2013 featuring 12 speakers. KF is also a sponsor of TEDWomen.
    - TED Conference, TEDWomen Conference (Box 1)
    - W. Gerald Austen Interview - Disk 1, 2012 April (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 5141
      Raw footage of an interview with Jerry Austen, retired KF trustee, at his office in Boston, Mass. Interview was conducted by Dennis Scholl. Three discs. Disc 3 is just footage of the awards and artifacts in Dr. Austen's office.
    - W. Gerald Austen Interview - Disk 2, 2012 April (Box 1)
    - W. Gerald Austen Interview - Disk 3, 2012 April (Box 1)
    - The Chapman Leadership Honors, 2013 October 3 (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 5290
      The Chapman Leadership Honors at Florida International University in Miami honored Alberto Ibarguen with its Transcendent Leadership Award. The DVD consists of three parts: a video tribute to Alberto featuring photographs (some personal) and tributes, including a tribute from Dave Lawrence; a video tribute to Alvah Chapman, featuring Betty Chapman; and Alberto's acceptance speech and award presentation.
    - A Glimpse of Life: The Pulitzer Photographs, 2009 (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 5542
      Newseum-produced, feature film features Pulitzer Prize winning photographers describing their photos and work. It is a companion piece to the book, edited by Eric Newton, and traveling exhibit sponsored by KF. 19 minutes.
    - Ideas in Motion: Knight Arts Challenge, 2010 (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 5574
      Stories of five Knight Arts Challenge winners in Miami - Florida Grand Opera, Sweat Records, Turned Based Press, Free Gospel Sunday and Teatro Avante. Also features interviews with Alberto Ibarguen and Dennis Scholl (27 minutes).
    - Knight Arts Challenge, c. 2009 (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 5575
      Stories of Knight Arts Challenge winners in Miami. Also features interviews with Alberto Ibarguen, Trabian Shorters and Dennis Scholl. Two versions: (6:24 minutes and 23 minutes)
    - Knight Arts Challenge - Version II, c. 2009 (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 5775
      Stories of Knight Arts Challenge winners in Miami. Also features interviews with Alberto Ibarguen, Trabian Shorters and Dennis Scholl.
  - Thumb Drive, 2011-2013; 4; 0.1 Cubic Feet
    - Newseum at 5 Featuring Alberto Ibarguen, 2013 April 11 (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 5220
      Thumb Drive containing a one minute video (1280 x 720, quick time format) celebrating the fifth anniversary of the Newseum in Washington, DC. Alberto Ibarguen, who served as the chair of the Newseum trustees, is featuring three times: at the dedication ceremony and twice speaking on press freedom. He says, "When you practice free speech, you strengthen free speech."
    - KF Website Records Day Backup, 2011 May (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 4914
      Containing information from the KF website on the Knight Arts Challenge, Knight News Challenge.
    - KF Website Records Day Backup, 2011 May (Box 1)
      Containing and KF photos, including staff and trustee photos.
    - Media Learning Seminar, 2012 (Box 1)
      Knight File Number - 5283
      Thumb drive sent to participants in the Media Learning Seminar 2012 with advance reading for the two-day meeting. Includes video welcomes from Alberto Ibarguen and Trabian Shorters.
- Video Recordings, 1986-2007; 3; 2.19 Cubic Feet 5 card file boxes
  When requesting to view audiovisual material, please refer to the Title and the AV Number (example: AV 1916). Researchers are asked to check the "Restrictions" note for each Title. If a Title does not currently have an access copy, please contact a RAC archivist for further instruction.
  - NCDI Video, 1991 March 12; VHS (Box 1, Tape AV 13116)
    Knight File Number - 736
    1991 video explaining the philosophy behind the National Community Development Initiative (NCDI), how it works and its accomplishments. 1 VHS tape. Approx. 20 minutes.
    Access copy currently unavailable. Please contact a RAC archivist for further instruction.
  - National Community Development Initiative: An Investment that Works, undated; VHS; 10 minutes (Box 1, Tape AV 13117)
    Knight File Number - 737
    Undated video documenting the National Community Development Initiative (NCDI), how it works and its accomplishments.
  - Local Initiatives Support Corporation: "Campaign for Communities", 1992 October 6; VHS; 11 minutes (Box 1, Tape AV 13118)
    Knight File Number - 739
    1992 video by Local Initiatives Support Corporation (LISC), which is supported by Knight Foundation through the National Community Development Corporation (NCDI). The video documents LISC's goal of supporting community development.
  - Immunization Initiative, undated; VHS; 10 minutes (Box 1, Tape AV 13119)
    Knight File Number - 740
    Undated video documenting the Knight Foundation's Immunization Initiative. Includes interviews with participating health care organizations, and other participants.
  - Knight Commission Press Conference, 1992 March 17; VHS; 2 hours (Box 1, Tape AV 13120)
    Knight File Number - 741
    1992 videotaped press conference of the Knight Commission on Intercollegiate Athletics. Speakers include Creed Black and Father Theodore Hesburgh. The conference discussed the reaction to and the effects of the Commission's report which was released one year earlier, and the Commission's next steps.
  - Knight Commission on Intercollegiate Athletics, 1991 September 1; VHS; 20 minutes (Box 1, Tape AV 13121)
    Knight File Number - 742
    This video was produced by Knight Foundation and the Knight Commission on Intercollegiate Athletics to send to the presidents of colleges and universities to inform them of the Commission's purpose, its research into the abuses in college athletics, and its conclusions as to reforms needed. It summarizes the findings published in the Commission's report, and is hosted by Creed Black.
  - Lee Hills Hall Dedication, 1995 December 20; VHS; 56 minutes (Box 1, Tape AV 13122)
    Knight File Number - 745
    1995 dedication of Lee Hills Hall at the University of Missouri School of Journalism, Columbia, MO. Speakers include Creed Black and Lee Hills.
  - Centre College Commencement, 1996 June 2; VHS; 2 hours, 30 minutes (Box 1, Tape AV 13123)
    Knight File Number - 749
    Creed Black delivered the commencement address to Centre College in 1996.
  - Charlotte Observer: Rolfe Neil Speech on Kids Voting, 1996 April 29; VHS; 10 minutes (Box 1, Tape AV 13124)
    Knight File Number - 750
    Rolfe Neill's speech on the Kids Voting program.
  - National Television highlights on Kids Voting, undated; VHS; 21 minutes (Box 1, Tape AV 13125)
    Knight File Number - 751
    National television highlights of the Kids Voting program.
  - Kids Voting USA Overview, 1995 May 9; VHS; 10 minutes (Box 1, Tape AV 13126)
    Knight File Number - 752
    Overview of the Kids Voting program.
  - Florida Philanthropy Conference, 1997 September 5; VHS; 10 minutes (Box 1, Tape AV 13127)
    Knight File Number - 753
    Promotional video of Florida Philanthropy, an organization of which Knight Foundation is a member, and highlights from the September, 1997 conference.
  - 60 Minutes report: The Final Four, undated; VHS; 15 minutes (Box 1, Tape AV 13128)
    Knight File Number - 754
    This undated story from the television show "60 Minutes" reports on the problem of athletic shoe manufacturers paying college athletic coaches to make their athletes wear their shoes for advertising purposes. The report illustrates the problems associated with big money in college athletics. The Knight Commission's report and recommendations for reform in this area is mentioned.
  - Medill: Building on 75 Years of Excellence, 1996 October; VHS; 15 minutes (Box 1, Tape AV 13129)
    Knight File Number - 755
    This video documents the history and success of the Medill School of Journalism at Northwestern University. Knight Foundation funded the Newspaper Management Center at the Medill School. No mention of KF is made in this video.
  - Tribute to Lewis Owens, undated; VHS; 7 minutes (Box 1, Tape AV 13130)
    Knight File Number - 756
    This tribute to Lewis Owens (publisher of the Lexington Herald-Leader) includes comments by Creed Black.
  - Grand Forks Herald: After the Flood, 1998 April 14-17; VHS; 55 minutes (Box 1, Tape AV 13131)
    Knight File Number - 1092
    WPLG-10 ABC Miami. "Nightline stories on the Grand Forks Herald: Come Hell and High Water, and After the Flood."
  - Introduction of Creed Black, by William Friday, 1998 May 22; VHS; 4 minutes (Box 1, Tape AV 13132)
    Knight File Number - 1093
    William Friday's introduction of Creed Black, at dinner in honor of Creed's retirement from the Knight Foundation.
  - Creed C. Black Video Presentation in Honor of his Retirement from the Knight Foundation, 1998 May 22; VHS; 8 minutes (Box 1, Tape AV 13133)
    Knight File Number - 1094
    Video presentation of Creed C. Black, shown at dinner in honor of Creed's retirement from the Knight Foundation. Focuses on Creed's contributions to the state of Kentucky. Includes comments from grantees in the Lexington, KY area.
  - Creed C. Black Video Presentation in Honor of his Retirement from the Knight Foundation, 1998 May 22; VHS; 8 minutes (Box 1, Tape AV 13134)
    Knight File Number - 1095
  - Grant Your Wish: How to Write a Successful Grant Proposal, 1998 December 31; VHS; 30 minutes (Box 2, Tape AV 13135)
    Knight File Number - 1118
    "Grant Your Wish: Learn from the Professionals How to Write a Successful Grant Proposal," by Successful Images, 1998. Features Creed Black. Endorsed on back cover by Creed Black as "the most in depth video on grant writing in the market today. It will help your nonprofit reap enormous financial rewards."
  - Firing Line Miniseries on Education, undated; VHS (Box 2, Tape AV 13136)
    Knight File Number - 1155
    Videotape series of PBS' "Firing Line," including the miniseries on education, "Liberal Education on the Firing Line," Dates unknown.
  - Knight Commission Report on College Sports, 2001 June 26-July 6; VHS (Box 2, Tape AV 13137)
    Knight File Number - 2388
    One video cassette re: "Knight Commission Report of College Sports". This is a compilation of broadcast commentary on the release of the report.
  - Firing Line Miniseries on Education: Resolved: We Need Not Fear the Religious Right, undated; VHS (Box 2, Tape AV 13138)
    Knight File Number - 2419
    Videotape series of PBS' "Firing Line," including the miniseries on education, "Resolved: We Need Not Fear the Religious Right."
  - Bill Moyers Report: Sports for Sale, 1991 March 19; VHS; 2 hours, 30 minutes (Box T5)
    Knight File Number - 2555
    Bill Moyers special, "Sports for Sale" on abuses in college basketball and football programs. The first half of the tape consists of the documentary. The second half is a panel discussion about the recommendations featured in the Knight Commission on ICA report released that day. Father Hesburgh and William Friday, co-chairs of the commission, are included in the panel discussion, as are Dick Schultz, Executive Director of the NCAA, former college president, Clifton Wharton, Jr., football coach LaVell Edwards and author Murray Sperber.
  - College Athletics Outside the Lines, 2000 January 21; VHS; 24 minutes (Box 2)
    Knight File Number - 2389
    One video cassette re: "College Athletics Outside the Lines", ESPN-TV Network, January 21, 2000, 9:30 - 10:00am.
  - Senator John Edwards and College Gambling, 2001 January 23; VHS (Box 2, Tape AV 13140)
    Knight File Number - 2390
    One video cassette re: "Senator John Edwards and College Gambling". This is a compilation of broadcast commentary.
  - Meeting of Knight Chairs/Midcareer Program Directors, AEJMC Convention, Kansas City, MO - Tape 1, 2003 July 29; MiniDV (Box 2, Tape AV 13141)
    Knight File Number - 2479
    McPhee, Alves, Gaines, McAdams - The meetings took place at the Association for Education in Journalism and Mass Communication in Kansas City, Missouri. The discussions focused on the use of new media to reach and teach people and the uses of the web for impact.
  - Meeting of Knight Chairs/Midcareer Program Directors, AEJMC Convention, Kansas City, MO - Tape 2, 2003 July 29; MiniDV (Box 2, Tape AV 13142)
    Knoght File Number - 2479
    The meetings took place at the Association for Education in Journalism and Mass Communication in Kansas City, Missouri. The discussions focused on the use of new media to reach and teach people and the uses of the web for impact.
  - Meeting of Knight Chairs/Midcareer Program Directors, AEJMC Convention, Kansas City, MO - Tape 3, 2003 July 29; MiniDV (Box 2, Tape AV 13143)
    Knight File Number 2479
    Lunch: Vicky Porter - The meetings took place at the Association for Education in Journalism and Mass Communication in Kansas City, Missouri. The discussions focused on the use of new media to reach and teach people and the uses of the web for impact.
  - Meeting of Knight Chairs/Midcareer Program Directors, AEJMC Convention, Kansas City, MO - Tape 4
  - Meeting of Knight Chairs/Midcareer Program Directors, AEJMC Convention, Kansas City, MO - Tape 5
  - Meeting of Knight Chairs/Midcareer Program Directors, AEJMC Convention, Kansas City, MO - Tape 1, 2003 July 29; VHS (Box T5)
  - Meeting of Knight Chairs/Midcareer Program Directors, AEJMC Convention, Kansas City, MO - Tape 2, 2003 July 29; VHS (Box T5)
  - Meeting of Knight Chairs/Midcareer Program Directors, AEJMC Convention, Kansas City, MO - Tape 3, 2003 July 29; VHS (Box T5)
  - Remarks by Creed Black at the Galef Institute, 1995 January 3; Betacam (Box T5)
    Knight File Number - 2556
    Announcement of $1 million grant (Grant #94-370). Penny McPhee may be included at announcement. Beta tape - could not be viewed.
  - Football for Credit, 2004 September 11 (Box T6)
    Knight File Number - 4449
    Two videotape copies (one VHS, one Beta SP) of an NBC Sports documentary program on the topic of Football for Credit, the practice at some universities with large football programs to grant academic credit for varsity players. Hodding Carter and Bill Friday were among several experts interviewed for the show. Both were critical of the practice. The work of the Knight Commission, and its reports, was mentioned.
  - Alberto Ibarguen Announcement, 2005 January 28; MiniDV (Box T6)
    Knight File Number - 4413
    One mini digital videotape of the announcement of Alberto Ibarguen being named president of the Knight Foundation.
  - Alberto Ibarguen Announcement - Knight News Challenge, c. 2007; MiniDV (Box T6)
    Knight File Number - 4414
    One mini digital videotape about the Knight News Challenge.
  - Good Beginnings Never End - Long Beach City College, undated; VHS (Box T6)
    Knight File Number - 2745
    Video, prepared by the Long Beach City College Instructional Media Production Services, provides testimonials and descriptions of a collaborative effort to bring services into the homes of home-based child service providers.
  - Video History of Charles Clark, 2004 December 22; Betacam (Box T6)
    Knight File Number - 3313
    One Beta videotape of an interview with Charles Clark, former Knight Foundation trustee. Clark was interviewed by Hodding Carter (off camera). The interview concentrated on Clark's experiences at Knight Foundation and the Knight brothers. No transcript was made.
  - Video History of Alvah Chapman - Part 1, 2004 December 22; Betacam (Box T6)
    Knight File Number - 3314